前情提要
现在全世界都疯了
World's a crazy place right now.
同盟被撕裂了
Alliances are all torn apart.
世界破碎了
The world's broken.
象征的意义来自赋予它们意义的
Symbols are nothing without the women and men
男男女女
that give them meaning.
谢谢你  美国队长  但这是你的
Thank you, Captain America. But this belongs to you.
给我讲讲你最近做的噩梦
Tell me about your most recent nightmare.
听着  我知道你经历了很多
Look, I know that you have been through a lot,
可你找回了自己的意志
but you've got your mind back,
你得到了赦免
you are being pardoned.
你自由了
You're free.
我可以做什么
To do what?
哎呦  看
Oh, bam! Right there!
看到他们了吗  他们是你需要担心的人
You see these guys? These are the guys you gotta worry about.
人人影视
原创翻译  双语字幕
字幕组招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
他们自称碎旗者
They call themselves Flag Smashers.
这些人想要一个统一无国界的世界
They want a world that's unified without borders.
翻译    草草  三四月  小酸奶
这就是碎旗者的领导者吗
So, this is the leader of the Flag Smashers, huh?
他力气很大
He's strong.
翻译    盐仔爱吃甜  杏仁斯嘉丽
天啊  山姆  你快来看
Oh, my God, Sam. You better look at this.
让我们一起欢迎新美国队长
Join me in welcoming your new Captain America.
校对    杏仁斯嘉丽
时间轴    树  大葱
后期    吉吉
总监    Eunice
回顾旧荣光呢
Reliving the glory days?
我还记得每场比赛前
I remember sneaking into this locker room
溜进这间更衣室来见你
before each game to see you.
这或许就是我们稳赢不输的秘诀
It's probably why we always won.
你紧张吗
You nervous?
谁  我吗
Who, me?
从不会
Never.
我做过队长  这当然不一样
I've been a captain before, obviously, but this is different.
这...
This is...
全世界的人
Everybody in the world
都指望我是某个样子
expects me to be something.
我不想让他们失望
And I don't wanna fail them.
-我知道  -嗯
- I know. - Yeah.
-做自己  -嗯
- Be yourself. - Yeah.
他们会喜欢你的
They're gonna love you.
祝你好运
Good luck.
-爱你  -爱你
- Love you. - Love you.
-他吐了吗  -还没呢  到你了
- Did he puke yet? - Not yet. You're up.
-收到  -早上好
- Copy that. - Good morning.
早上好  美国  早上好
Good morning, America. Good morning.
不对  你是美国队长  你不是...
No, you're Captain America, you're not...
早上好  约翰  队长
Good morning. John, Captain, uh...
美国队长
Captain America.
所以你戏剧课没过
And that's why you failed drama class.
-你能相信吗  -是啊
- Can you believe this? - I know, right?
-嗯  -两周前我们还在组队
- Yeah. - Two weeks ago we're prepping the team
准备去智利执行特种任务  现在来干这个
for a special ops mission in Chile, now this.
别误会  这很好
Don't get me wrong, this has been great,
很好  但我握了好多手
it's been great, but it's been a lot of handshakes,
好多装扮  发表了好多讲话
a lot of suits, a lot of speeches,
还有跟参议员见面
and senator meetings,
我只想好好工作
and I just wanna do the job.
-这就是你的工作  约翰  -嗯
- This is the job, John. - Yeah.
这一切都是
All of it is.
胸有成竹的星条旗之子  什么的
Star-spangled man with a plan and all that.
那本就是工作的一部分
It's always been in the job description.
这身衣服  是满载着期待的  兄弟
Listen, this suit, it comes with expectations, brother.
你今后不能靠蛮力解决问题了
You can't just punch your way out of problems anymore, you know?
该去工作了
Time to go to work.
猎鹰与冬兵
第一季  第二集
谢谢
Thank you.
美国队长
早安美国
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen...
你们的新美国队长
Your new Captain America!
早上好  美国
Good morning, America.
好啊
Yeah!
非常感谢你能来
Thank you so much for coming.
你一定很开心吧
This has gotta be fun, though,
时过境迁  再回到你的高中
coming back to your high school after so much has changed?
-约翰·沃克  -真是太棒了
- John Walker! - Oh, it's great. We're...
好啊
Yeah.
约翰  我想大家最想知道的事
John, I think the first thing everyone wants to know
就是做美国队长是什么感觉
is what is it like being Captain America?
你走到哪儿头顶都有老鹰飞过吗
Do eagles fly overhead wherever you go?
是啊
Uh, yes.
是的  还有国旗会威武地在空中飘扬
Yeah, that and flags tend to start majestically waving in the wind.
巡演如何
And how's the tour been?
我知道他们为你安排了盛大的首秀
I know they did a big rollout for you, right?
真是莫大荣幸
It's the greatest honor of my life.
但我还有些震惊
Um, but I'm just a little shocked, I think.
我这样的人怎么会走到这一步
How did a guy like me end up here?
等等  "我这样的人"
Oh, wait, wait, wait. "A guy like me"?
某人太自谦了
Somebody's being a bit too humble.
如果你们不了解约翰的简历
For those of you who aren't familiar with his résumé,
约翰·沃克成为美国队长
佐治亚州  卡斯特林高中
"约翰·沃克  美国历史上
"John Walker, first person in American history
荣获三枚荣誉勋章第一人
to receive three Medals of Honor,
曾负责绝密反恐任务和人质救援任务"
ran RS-One missions in counterterrorism and hostage rescue."
政府在麻省理工学院研究过你的身体
The government did a study of your body at MIT,
你在所有可测量门类中都成绩斐然
and you tested off the charts in every measurable category.
速度  耐力  智力
Speed, endurance, intelligence...
是这样的  我不是托尼·斯塔克
Look, here's the thing, uh, I'm not Tony Stark,
也不是班纳博士
I'm not Dr. Banner, okay?
我没有酷炫装备  或超级力量
I don't have the flashiest gadgets, I don't have super strength.
但我有
But what I do have
勇气
is guts.
那是美国队长一直拥有
Something Captain America always had,
也一直需要的东西  我会需要一切勇气
always needs to have, and I'm gonna need every ounce of it.
因为  我要接过重大的责任
Because I got big shoes to fill.
你认识史蒂夫·罗杰斯吗
Did you know Steve Rogers?
史蒂夫回归时
Well, I was two years out of West Point
我已离开西点两年了
when Steve came back on the scene.
他做复仇者时  我一直密切关注他
I followed his career very closely as an Avenger.
我认为我以他为榜样
I like to think that I modeled my work after his.
所以你一直想做个英雄吗
So you've always wanted to be a hero?
我很高兴我做的事能给人们安全感
I liked that what I was doing would make people feel safe.
史蒂夫·罗杰斯就是有这种本事的人
Steve Rogers was the kind of guy who could do that,
他给了我希望
he gave me hope.
虽然我没见过他
Even though I never met him,
却觉得他如同我的兄弟
he feels like a brother.
队长回归
看上去人不错
Seems like a good guy.
队长回归  约翰·沃克
-你见过他吗  -没有
- You met him? - No.
谢谢你这么急能赶来
Thanks for doing this on such short notice.
没事  我就再检查几件事
Yeah. No sweat. I'm just finishing up the checklist.
你到慕尼黑后就一切就绪了
You'll be all good to go once you land in Munich.
不该放弃那盾的
Shouldn't have given up the shield.
见到你也很高兴  巴基
Good to see you too, Buck.
-这不对  -我在工作呢
- This is wrong. - Hey, hey, look, I'm working, all right?
你的愤怒只能等等了
So all this outrage is gonna have to wait.
你不知道会发生这种事吗
You didn't know that was gonna happen?
我当然不知道会发生这种事
No, of course I didn't know that was gonna happen.
你以为看到他们
You think it didn't break my heart
推出他来  喊他新美队
to see them march him out there
就没伤透我的心吗
and call him the new Captain America?
史蒂夫可没想这样
This isn't what Steve want.
天啊  那你要我怎么办
Oh, my God. What do you want me to do?
给美国打电话  告诉他们我改主意了吗
Call America and tell 'em I changed my mind? Huh?
是啊  重聚很高兴  兄弟  保重
Yeah, right. It's a great reunion, buddy, be well.
你无权放弃盾牌  山姆
You had no right to give up the shield, Sam.
你不能这样
This is what you're not gonna do.
你自己的生活都收拾不过来
You're not gonna come here in your overextended life
别跑来教训我有什么权利
and tell me about my rights.
结束了  巴基
It's over, Bucky.
再说  我现在还要处理更严重的事
Besides, I have bigger things to deal with now.
还有什么比这严重
What could be bigger than this?
这人
This guy.
他跟全东欧和中欧的反叛组织
His connections with rebel organizations
都有联系  他的力气还非常大
all over Eastern and Central Europe, and he's strong.
力气太大了
Too strong.
怎么了
And?
他跟一个网上组织
Well, he's been connected
碎旗者有关联
to this online group called the Flag Smashers.
红翼追踪他们
Now, Redwing traced them
到慕尼黑外的一栋建筑
to a building somewhere outside of Munich.
-所以我要去那里  -我不信任红翼
- So that's where I'm going. - Well, I don't trust Redwing.
-等等  -你不用信任红翼
- Hold on a minute. - You don't have to trust Redwing,
但我要去看看他是不是说对了
but I'mma go see if he's right.
因为我觉得他们可能是大三样里的
'Cause I have a feeling they might be a part of the Big Three.
-什么"大三样"  -大三样
- What "Big Three"? - The Big Three.
-什么大三样  -人形机器人  外星人  巫师
- What Big Three? - Androids, aliens, and wizards.
-才没这说法  -怎么没有
- That's not a thing. - That's definitely a thing.
就没有
No, it's not.
每次我们作战  都是跟这三样中的一样
Every time we fight, it's one of the three.
那你现在又在跟谁作战  甘道夫吗
Who are you fighting now, Gandalf?
你怎么知道甘道夫
How do you know about Gandalf?
1937年《霍比特人》刚出版时我就读过
I read The Hobbit in 1937 when it first came out.
-所以你明白我的意思了吧  -我不  巫师不存在
- So you see my point? - No, I don't. There are no wizards.
-奇异博士  -是个法师
- Doctor Strange. - Is a sorcerer.
法师就是不戴巫师帽的巫师
A sorcerer is a wizard without a hat.
想想吧  是吧
Think about it. Right?
我是对的  我才想出来的  多疯狂
I'm right. I just came up with that. It's crazy.
但那不是重点  这些人没魔法
But look, that's not the point. These guys aren't magical.
他们跟你一样用蛮力
All right. They use brute force like you,
就像我面前这个
the incredibly annoying guy
爱瞪眼的烦人家伙
in front of me with the staring problem.
-我跟你一起去  -别做梦了
- I'm coming with you. - No, you're not.
德国  慕尼黑
还有一分钟下机  山姆
One minute to drop off, Sam.
我们怎么打算的
So what's our plan?
好啊  没打算咯
Great. So no plan.
30秒
Thirty seconds!
-旅途愉快  巴基  -不  你不能那么喊我
- Enjoy your ride, Buck. - No, you can't call me that.
怎么了  史蒂夫就那么喊你
Why not? That's what Steve called you.
史蒂夫认识我更久  而且他总有计划
Steve knew me longer, and Steve had a plan.
15秒离机
Fifteen seconds to drop.
我有计划
I have a plan.
是吗
Really?
什么计划
What is it?
好啊
Great.
降落伞呢
Where's the chute?
这里是60米  太低空不能跳伞
We're at 200 feet, man. It's too low for a chute.
我反正也不需要
I don't need it anyway.
你确定吗
You sure about that?
嗯
Yeah.
我全拍下来了  你知道吧
I have all of that on camera. You know that, right?
滚远点  山姆  不然我揍暴它
Get out of my face, Sam, or I'll break it.
好吧  往北来  来吧
Okay, head north. Come on.
别伤害他
Don't hurt him.
你又在瞪了
You're doing the staring thing again.
他们在里面
They're in there.
-那人呢  -我不知道
- Where's the guy? - I don't know.
但他们好像在偷运军火
I think they're smuggling weapons, though.
你可能想对了
Well, I think you could be right.
但要一探究竟只有一个办法
But there's only one way to find out.
我看这条路很通畅  我们上吧
I see a clear path. I say we take it.
我们不是刺客
We're not assassins.
我们里面见  随你便
I'll see you inside or not.
拜托  伙计  我闹你呢  回来
Hey, come on, man. I'm just messing with you. Come back.
看看你  蹑手蹑脚
Look at you. All stealthy.
在瓦坎达待了一阵  就变成白豹了
A little time in Wakanda and you come out White Panther.
是白狼
It's actually White Wolf.
好  我进来了  所以我比你领先好多
All right, I'm inside. Therefore, way ahead of you.
虽然不是特别理想  但很可行
It's not great, but very doable.
你好  你好吗
Hello. How are you?
很好  我错过了什么  什么都没有
Good. What did I miss? Nothing.
-好  走吧  -不  等等
- All right, let's go. - No, wait.
我有振金手臂  我拿得下他们
I got a vibranium arm. I can take them.
我还能飞呢  谁在乎  等着
And I can fly. Who gives a shit? Wait.
-我想看到他们往哪去  -他们就俩人
- I want to see where they're going. - There's two people.
-你就看到俩吗  -我看是俩
- You only see two? - That's what I saw.
-我看看红翼看到了什么  -好吧
- Let me see what Redwing sees. - All right.
我看看  看看红翼...
Let me see. Let's see what Redwing...
看啊  你现在看到多少人了
Oh, look at that. How many people you see now?
一  二...又来了
One, two... Oh, here it comes again.
-四  五  -好吧  五个
- Four. Five. - Yeah, five. Yeah.
他们力气很大  随便了
So they're strong. Whatever.
-好  我们上吧  -不  等等
- All right, let's go. - No, no, wait.
该死
Shit.
好了  我们走
All right, let's move.
我们走
Let's move. Yeah.
那是第八个人  他们可能有人质
There's an eighth person. I think they have a hostage.
保持冷冻
他们在偷药物  疫苗
They're stealing medicine. Vaccines.
疫苗运输
巴基  说话  什么情况
Bucky, talk to me. What's goin' on?
找到人质了
Found the hostage.
你还好吧
You okay?
奥斯纳布吕克公司
该死
Shit.
我一直想那么干来着
I always wanted to do that.
你可算是参战了  山姆
Good of you to join the fight, Sam!
山姆  我是约翰·沃克  美国队长
Sam. John Walker, Captain America.
莱玛·霍斯金斯
Lemar Hoskins.
似乎你们二位需要搭把手
Looks like you guys can use some help.
你被那小丫头痛扁
That little girl kicked your ass.
约翰  你在哪
John, where you at, man?
后悔没盾牌傍身了吧
Could have used that shield.
你起开
Get off of me.
那些全是超级战士  山姆
Those were all Super Soldiers, Sam.
我知道
I know.
对了  不客气
You're welcome, by the way.
我没事  我没事
I'm okay. I'm okay.
刚才那样可不好
That was a bad idea.
-很遗憾红翼不在了  -你才不遗憾
- Sorry about Redwing. - No, you're not.
你那半机器人的大脑在想什么
What's going on in that big cyborg brain of yours?
在计算
It's computing.
你知道吗  我能看得真切
You know what? I can actually see it.
我能看见齿轮在转
I can see the gears turning.
出故障了  不转了  烧着了
Oh, they're malfunctioning, shutting down. Yep, they're on fire.
我们得弄清楚血清的来源
We gotta figure out where the serum's coming from.
是啊  以及过了80年
Yeah. And how in the hell after 80 years
还有八名超级战士不受控  到底是怎么回事
are there eight Super Soldiers runnin' loose?
计划不太顺利
So that didn't go as planned, huh?
好吧
Okay.
我们继续开
Let's keep going.
至少我们知道了要对付什么
Look, at least we know what we're up against now, huh?
我们非常确定  是大三样之一
And we're pretty sure it's one of the Big Three, so...
-外星人  人形机器人或者巫师  -非常确定
- Aliens, androids, or wizards? - Pretty sure.
巫师不存在的
There's no such thing as wizards.
-那就是外星人  人形机器人...  -或者超级战士
- Alright. Then it's aliens, or androids... - Or Super Soldiers.
-超级战士  你认真的吗  -是啊
- Shit. Super Soldiers, for real? - Yeah.
好吧  那我们得合作
All right, well, then we gotta work together.
不可能
That's not happening.
胜算肯定要高得多  如果我们都...
I think we stand a much better chance if we all just...
你持那块盾牌
Just 'cause you carry that shield,
也并不代表你是美国队长
it doesn't mean you're Captain America.
我该做的都做了  好吗
Look, I've done the work, okay?
你用身体捂过手榴弹吗
You ever jump on top of a grenade?
捂过  其实我捂过四次呢
Yeah. Actually, I have. Four times.
我戴这头盔就是做这个的  这是强化过的头盔
It's a thing I do with my helmet. It's a reinforced helmet.
说来话长  但是...
It's a long story, but, any...
离机场还有三十多公里呢  你们需要搭车
Look, it's 20 miles to the airport. You guys need a ride.
二位  加里  停车  上来
Guys. Gary, stop. Get in.
情况是有八名超级战士在运输大宗货物
Okay, so we've got eight Super Soldiers on a bulk supply run.
为什么
Why?
他们说他们的任务是
They say their mission is
让一切恢复到"闪烁"期间的样子
to get things back to the way it was during The Blip.
也许他们只是想帮忙
Maybe they're just trying to help.
那他们表现的方式可够奇怪的
They had a funny way of showing it.
那血清的过去可不光彩  恕我直言
That serum doesn't exactly have a great track record. No offense.
我们得查清他们要去哪里
We need to figure out where they're going.
你们是怎么追踪他们到这里的  追踪碎旗者
How'd you track 'em here? The Flag Smashers?
不是的  我们没追踪他们
Uh, no, we didn't track them,
我们追踪的是你  通过红翼
we tracked you, uh, through Redwing.
你黑了我的科技
You hacked my tech?
抱歉  其实不算是"黑"
Sorry. It's not exactly hacking.
那是政府财产
It's government property.
我们也算是政府吧
Kind of the government.
他总是那样瞪人吗
Does he always just stare like that?
你会习惯的
You get used to it.
好了  事情变得有点...
Okay, look, you know, things have gotten kind of, uh...
混乱了
Chaotic.
对  全球回归委员会尽他们所能
Yeah. The GRC, they're doing the best they can
让世界在"闪烁"后顺利运转
to get things up and running smoothly, post Blip.
重新激活公民身份  社会保障  医疗保险
Reactivating citizenship, social security, healthcare.
基本上就是在帮助
Basically just managing resources
回归后流离失所的难民管理资源
for the refugees who were displaced by the return.
所有这些都是全球回归委员会在做
The Global Repatriation Council does all that.
这我懂
I get that.
那你俩到底为什么在这里
So why exactly are you two here?
他们提供资源
Well, they provide the resources
我们负责维稳
and we keep things stable.
对  暴力革命分子
Yeah, violent revolutionaries
通常对任何人的目标都没好处
aren't usually good for anyone's cause.
这话一般是掌握资源的人说的
Usually said by the people with the resources.
我们有许多资源
We got a lot of resources.
如果你们二位跟我们联手的话  我们就能...
If you guys, if you joined up with us, we could...
-不  -二位令我五体投地
- No. - I got mad respect for both of y'all.
但今天我们出场之前  你们好像被揍得落花流水
But you were getting your asses kicked till we showed up.
-你是谁  -莱玛·霍斯金斯
- Who are you? - Lemar Hoskins.
我看到一个
Look, I see a guy
身着战术装备的人挂在直升机外面
hanging out of a helicopter in tactical gear,
我需要的可远不止莱玛·霍斯金斯
I need a lot more than Lemar Hoskins.
我是战星  约翰的搭档
I'm Battlestar. John's partner.
"战星"
"Battlestar"?
停车
Stop the car!
听着  我懂  好吗
Look, I... I get it, okay?
我明白你的态度  真的
I get the attitude, I do.
你没想到盾牌会落到我手里
You didn't think that the shield was gonna end up here.
我懂  巴基
I get it, Bucky.
我...我不是想成为史蒂夫
And I'm... I'm not trying to be Steve.
我没想替代史蒂夫
I'm not trying to replace Steve.
我只是想成为我能成为的最优秀的美国队长
I'm just trying to be the best Captain America I can be.
就这样
That's it.
如果队长的左膀右臂
It'd be a whole lot easier
能在我身边  就会简单得多
if I had Cap's wingmen on my side.
总是最后一句话坏事
It's always that last line.
走吧
Let's go.
你们肯定快要饿死了
You must be famished.
-饿极了  -是啊
- Very hungry. - Yeah.
-对  我们饿了  -好  我妻子和我做了饭
- Yeah, we are hungry. - Okay. My wife and I cooked.
这是按我家祖传秘方做的
It's an old family recipe
用的是最好的鸡肝
made with the finest chicken livers.
随便吃吧
Please serve yourselves.
想要什么都可以  什么都行  尽管告诉我
Anything you want. Anything. You ask me.
这有咖啡  还有些饼干
There is some coffee here and some crackers.
-这些够了  谢谢  -为了大业  我们愿做一切
- We're okay. Thank you. - Uh, anything we can do for the cause.
请跟我来
Please follow me.
你们都快成为传奇人物了
You're becoming a bit of a legend.
我听到越来越多的人
I hear more and more people talk about
提起你们这些反抗的自由斗士
the freedom fighters who are pushing back.
他们叫你们侠盗罗宾汉
They call you Robin Hood.
每天都有越来越多的人喜爱你们
Every day more people love you.
你们所到之处  都会有人给予庇护
You'll find refuge wherever you go.
我和我妻子专为你们布置的
My wife and I made this just for you.
一切都非常干净
Everything is completely clean.
-不错  -她布置得温馨舒适
- Okay. - She made it really nice and cozy.
-谢谢你  -别客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
老天  能睡床了
Oh, my gosh, beds.
未知联系人  匿名号码
你夺走了我的东西
我会找到你  杀了你
这太棒了
That's real nice.
这种食物最适合你了  伙计
This has your name written all over it, bro.
希望你们住得舒适
Hope you feel comfortable.
明天见
Bis morgen!
-谢谢  -谢谢你
- Thank you. - Thank you.
床太小了
Too small.
该死  他们已经在通缉我们了
Shit. They're already looking for us.
我要把我们的化名从所有公共交通网站上抹去
I'm wiping our aliases off any public traffic sites now.
国际刑警组织通缉令
卡莉  我们不能在这里久留
Karli, we can't stay here for long.
通缉  卡莉·摩根索  最后出现在慕尼黑附近
持有武器  请格外谨慎应对
六个月前  你们能想象到
Six months ago would you have imagined
会有这么多人支持我们的大业吗
people supporting the cause like this?
我们不再小打小闹了
We're not playing no more.
我们不能让那些
We can't let these same assholes
在"闪烁"后重新掌权的混蛋赢
who were put back in power after The Blip win.
全球回归委员会更在乎那些回归者
The GRC care more about the people who came back
而不是那些从未消失的人
than the ones who never left.
我们已经窥见了更好的可能性
We got a glimpse of how things could be.
我需要确定你们都是真心参与的
I need to know that you're all committed,
因为明天之后  就再不能回头了
because after tomorrow, there's no going back.
没错  同一世界
Yeah. One world.
同一类人
One people.
-同一世界  -同一类人
- One world. - One people.
- One world! - One people!
你还好吗
You all right?
山姆  我们去把盾牌拿走吧
Let's take the shield, Sam.
拿走盾牌  然后我们单干
Let's take the shield and do this ourselves.
我们不能就这么冲到他面前
We can't just run up on the man,
把他揍一顿  然后拿走盾牌
beat him up, and take it.
你还记得我们上次偷盾牌之后发生的事吗
Do you remember what happened the last time we stole it?
-也许吧  -以防万一  我提醒你一下
- Maybe. - I'll help you in case you forgot.
莎伦被列为国家公敌
Sharon was branded enemy of the state,
史蒂夫和我逃亡了整整两年
and Steve and I were on the run for two years.
我不知道你怎么想的
I don't know about you,
我反正不想下半辈子都颠沛流离
but I don't wanna live the rest of my life la vida loca.
我们刚被那些超级士兵暴揍一通
We just got our ass handed to us by Super Soldiers,
却一无所获
and we got nothing.
也不完全是
Not entirely true.
有一个人你应该去见见
There is someone that you should meet.
马里兰州  巴尔的摩
-是黑猎鹰  你好  -孩子  就叫猎鹰
- It's Black Falcon. What's up? - It's just Falcon, kid.
不  不对  我爸告诉我你是黑猎鹰
No, no. My daddy told me it's Black Falcon.
是因为我是黑人也是猎鹰吗
Is it because I'm black and I'm the Falcon?
严格地说  是
Well, technically, I mean, yes.
那你是什么  黑孩子吗
So are you, like, Black kid?
他无话可说了吧
I got him, right?
随你便吧  伙计
Whatever, man.
随你便
Whatever.
禁止入内
我们是来见以赛亚的
We're here to see Isaiah.
这里没有什么以赛亚
Nobody named Isaiah live here.
我们只是想和他谈谈
Look, we just want to talk to him.
你没听见我刚才说的吗
You must not hear what I just said.
我不会让你进来的
You ain't getting in this house.
你们赶紧走吧
Y'all can leave now.
告诉他  高阳酒吧的那个人来见他了
Tell him the guy from the bar in Goyang is here.
他会明白我什么意思的
He's gonna know what that means.
好吧  在这儿等着
All right, wait here.
孩子挺好  你怎么认识这个人的
Nice kid. How do you know this guy?
以前的事了
I used to.
在朝鲜战争时我们有过一次小摩擦
We had a skirmish during the Korean War.
你们今天运气不错
Today's your lucky day.
他说他要亲自见你们
He said he wanna see for himself.
以赛亚
Isaiah?
看看你
Look at you.
这位是山姆  山姆  这是以赛亚
This is, uh, Sam. Sam, this is Isaiah.
他是一位英雄
He was a hero.
九头蛇最惧怕的人之一  就像史蒂夫一样
One of the ones that HYDRA feared the most. Like Steve.
我们是1951年认识的
We met in '51.
如果你说的"认识"是指我把你揍翻了
If by met, you mean I whupped your ass,
那你说得没错
then, yeah.
我们得到密报说他在朝鲜半岛
We heard whispers he was on the peninsula,
但是所有被派去抓他的人都有去无回
but everyone they sent after him, never came back.
所以美国军方
So the U.S. Military dropped me
让我深入敌后去对付他
behind the line to go deal with him.
高阳那次打斗中  我扯下了他半条金属手臂
I took half that metal arm in that fight in Goyang,
但我看他又想办法长回来了
but I see he's managed to grow it back.
让你们进来  我就想看看他手臂恢复没有
I just wanted to see if he got the arm back.
或者他是不是来杀我的
Or if he'd come to kill me.
我不再是杀手了
I'm not a killer anymore.
你觉得你能某天醒来
You think you can wake up one day
决定自己想成为什么人吗
and decide who you wanna be?
不是那样的
It doesn't work like that.
也许你这样的人是可以的
Well, maybe it does for folks like you.
以赛亚  我们来这里是因为
Isaiah, the reason we're here
出现了更多你我这样的人
is because there's more of you and me out there.
-你我这样的人  -我们要知道是怎么回事
- You and me. - And we need to know how.
我不要再谈这件事了
I'm not gonna talk about it anymore.
你知道他们是怎么对待我这个英雄的吗
You know what they did to me for being a hero?
他们把我关进监狱30年
They put my ass in jail for 30 years.
不断有人给我做检测
People running tests,
抽我的血  进入我的牢房
taking my blood, coming into my cell.
甚至连你的同类也不放过我
Even your people weren't done with me.
-以赛亚  -从我家里滚出去
- Isaiah... - Get out of my house!
走吧  出去吧
Let's go, man, let's go.
-山姆  -你为什么没跟我说起过以赛亚
- Sam... - Why didn't you tell me about Isaiah?
怎么从来都没人提起过他
How could nobody bring him up?
-我问你话呢  巴基  -我知道
- I asked you a question, Bucky. - I know.
史蒂夫也不知道他
Steve didn't know about him?
不知道  我没跟他说
He didn't. I didn't tell him.
所以你是说  几十年前有个黑人超级战士
So you're telling me that there was a black Super Soldier
但是却没人知道
decades ago and nobody knew about it?
怎么了  两位
What's up, man?
-有什么问题吗  -没  我们聊天呢
- Is there a problem here? - No, we're just talking.
我们没事
We're fine.
我能看看你的证件吗
Can I see your ID?
-我没有证件  怎么了  -没搞错吧你
- I don't have ID. Why? - Man, seriously?
先生  冷静点
Okay, sir, just calm down.
我很冷静  你们想干什么  我们只是站着聊天而已
I am calm. What do you want? We're just standing and talking.
-把你的证件给他  我们就能走了  -我他妈才不要
- Give him your ID so we can leave. - No. I'm not giving him shit.
-我们只是在聊天  -他缠着你不放吗
- We're just talking. - Is he bothering you?
他没有缠着我不放  你知道他是谁吗
No, he's not bothering me. Do you know who this is?
这两位是复仇者
These guys are Avengers.
天啊  实在是对不起  威尔逊先生
Oh, God, I am so sorry, Mr. Wilson.
没戴护目镜我都认不出您了
I didn't recognize you without the goggles.
实在抱歉
I'm really, really sorry about this.
两位先在这等一下好吗
Guys, just wait here, okay? Just...
我没跟任何人说
I didn't... I didn't tell anybody
因为他已经受了太多苦
because he had already been through enough.
巴恩斯先生
Mr. Barnes,
我们有一张你的逮捕令
there's a warrant out for your arrest.
总统都已经赦免他了
Look, the president pardoned him for all that.
不  是因为你没去法庭强制的心理治疗
Not for that. You missed your court-mandated therapy.
你没在规定的时间跟假释官报到
It's like missing a check-in with your PO.
很抱歉  巴纳斯先生  你被捕了
I'm sorry, Mr. Barnes, you're under arrest.
山姆  久仰大名
Sam. I've heard a lot about you.
我是雷纳医生  詹姆斯的心理医生
I'm Dr. Raynor. I'm James's therapist.
幸会  感谢你捞他出来
So nice to meet you. Thank you for getting him out.
不是我
That was not me.
克里斯蒂娜
Christina.
很高兴再次见到你
It's great to see you again.
开玩笑吧  你认识他
You gotta be kidding me. You know him?
对  我们以前一起出过外勤
Yeah, we did some field ops back in the day.
我听说你在给巴基做心理治疗
I heard you were working with Bucky,
所以我觉得我该出手了
so I thought I'd step in.
巴基不需要再严格按时去见你了
Bucky's not gonna be following a strict schedule any longer.
治疗还没结束呢  谁批准的
We haven't finished our work. Who authorized this?
他这样的人才不应该被束缚
He's too valuable of an asset to have tied up.
你就给他治疗完
Just do whatever you got to do with him,
然后把他交给我
then send him off to me.
我跟他还有事没解决
Got some unfinished business, him and I.
你也是  威尔逊  我在外面等你们
You too, Wilson. I'll be outside.
詹姆斯  放了你的条件是
James, condition of your release,
现在开始心理咨询  你也一样  山姆
session now. You too, Sam.
好的  我会在外面和...
That's okay. I'll be out here with...
我不是在和你商量
That wasn't a request.
那么
So...
谁想先说
Who would like to start?
好了  雷纳医生
All right, look, Dr. Raynor?
我知道你为什么想让我和这位
I get it, why you want me to talk to
时常脱线的怪人谈话
Freaky Magoo over here.
但是我心理非常健康
But I'm 100% fine.
我的职责就是确认你真的没问题
It is my job to make sure that you're okay.
所以  虽然有点不专业
And so, yeah, this may be slightly unprofessional,
但是只有通过这一方式
but it's the only way that I can see
我才能知道你是否能克服内心恐惧
if you're getting over whatever's eating at you.
-这太扯了  -我同意
- This is ridiculous. - Yeah. I agree.
看到了吗  已经有进展了
See? Making progress already.
那么  谁想先来
So, who wants to go first?
没人主动来吗
No volunteers?
真是意外
Wow. How surprising.
好  我们现在做个练习
Okay. We're going to do an exercise.
每当有夫妻想搞清楚
It's something I use with couples
他们想共同构建怎样的生活时
when they are trying to figure out
我都会用这个练习
what kind of life they wanna build together.
你们听说过奇迹问题吗
Are you familiar with the miracle question?
-闻所未闻  -见所未见
- Absolutely not. - Of course not.
这个练习是这样的
Okay, it goes like this.
假设在你睡觉的时候出现了一个奇迹
Suppose that while you're sleeping, a miracle occurs.
你醒来之后
When you wake up,
你希望看到什么
what is something that you would like to see
能让你的生活变好的事
that would make your life better?
我的奇迹就是  他能少说点话
In my miracle, he would... he would talk less.
和我想说的一模一样  真够讽刺的
Exactly what I was gonna say. Isn't that ironic?
是你们俩逼我的
You guys are leaving me with no choice.
现在该进行灵魂凝视练习了
It's time for the soul-gazing exercise.
-我更喜欢这个  -天哪  他肯定会喜欢的
- I like this better. - Oh, God. He's gonna love this.
-我准备好了  -这正合你的口味
- Yeah, I'm ready. - This is right up your alley.
转过来  面对彼此
Turn around. Face each other.
你肯定会乐在其中
You should really enjoy this.
可不是嘛
I'm going to.
我知道你会
I know you are.
山姆  面对面
Sam. Face each other.
来吧  试试灵魂凝视
Let's do it. Let's stare.
-靠近点  -这个练习真不错  谢谢你医生
- Get close. -This is a good exercise. Thanks, Doc.
很好  再靠近点
All right, good. All right, get close.
再靠近一点点
Come on, a little closer.
你的腿想放哪边
Which way you want to go?
-右还是左  -你的腿怎么是张开的
- Right or left? - Why're your legs open?
这样  你满意了吗
You know what? Fine. Here. You happy now?
-行了  -就这样
- All right. - All right.
-很好  -我们动不了了
- Good. Fine. - We're locked in.
-有点近了  -是非常近
- That's a little close. - That's very close.
不正合你意吗
That's what you wanted, right?
两位
Guys.
很好  现在看着彼此
Good. Now look at each other.
你们要看着对方的眼睛
You need to look at each other in the eyes.
你看  也没有那么难
There, you see? That wasn't so hard.
等等  你们在干什么
Wait, what are you doing?
你们俩在瞪眼比赛吗
Are you having a staring contest?
眨眨眼  上帝啊
Just blink. Sweet Jesus.
好了  詹姆斯  山姆哪里惹到你了
All right, James, why does Sam aggravate you?
别说幼稚的话
And don't say something childish.
你为什么放弃了盾牌
Why did you give up that shield?
你为什么要这么在意
Why are you making such a big deal
一件跟你没有任何关系的事
out of something that has nothing to do with you?
史蒂夫相信你
Steve believed in you.
他信任你
He trusted you.
他把盾给你是有原因的
He gave you that shield for a reason.
那块盾  那是他守护的一切
That shield, that is... that is everything he stood for.
那是他的传承
That is his legacy.
他把盾给了你
He gave you that shield,
你却根本不当一回事  直接扔了
and you threw it away like it was nothing.
-闭嘴  -也许他是看错你了
- Shut up. - So maybe he was wrong about you.
如果他看错了你
And if he was wrong about you,
那他也看错了我
then he was wrong about me.
说完了吗
You finished?
-嗯  -很好
- Yeah. - All right, good.
也许你和史蒂夫
Maybe this is something you or Steve
永远不可能理解
will never understand.
但是你能不能接受  我做了我认为正确的选择
But can you accept that I did what I thought was right?
医生  我不想再这样浪费时间了
You know what, Doc? I don't have time for this.
我们还有很重要的事要做
We have some real serious shit going on.
不如这样吧
So how about this?
这件事我再也不纠结了
I will squash it right now.
我们办完那件事以后
We go deal with that, and when we're done,
就分道扬镳  享受一段漫长的假期
we both can go on separate, long vacations
永不相见了
and never see each other again.
-这主意不错  -很好
- I like that. - Great.
那我们开始吧
Well, let's get to work.
医生  谢谢你弄了这一出尴尬事
Thanks, Doc, for making it weird.
我感觉可是好多了
I feel much better.
我在外面等你
I'll see you outside.
谢谢你才是
Thank you.
真是太好了
That was really great.
我熟悉这个表情  怎么了
I know that look. What's wrong?
第二条规则是什么来着
What was rule number two again?
不许让任何人受伤
Don't hurt anyone.
再见  医生
Goodbye, Doc.
我觉得好多了
Well, I feel better.
我觉得糟透了
I feel awful.
先生们
Gentlemen.
再次见到你们真是太好了
Good to see you again.
如果我们搞分裂  就只会失败
Look, if we divide ourselves, we don't stand a chance,
你们都很清楚的
you guys know that.
那现在是什么情况
So what do you got?
他们的领导者名叫卡莉·摩根索
Well, the leader's name's Karli Morgenthau.
我们一直在追查那些
We've been targeting civilians
帮助卡莉四处流窜的平民
who've been helping Karli move from place to place.
他们标记一个地点  然后干扰信号
They geotagged a location, then scrambled the signal.
但是我们的卫星在欧洲中部和东部的
But our satellites have found their symbol popping up
多个回归安置社区
in various displaced communities
发现了他们的象征
all across Central and Eastern Europe.
我们觉得她把刚偷的药
We think that she's taking the medicine
带到了其中一个营地里
she just stole to one of these camps.
"闪烁"之后
Well, there are hundreds of those
全球冒出了几百个这种营地
all over the planet since The Blip.
看来你们得费大功夫好好找了
So I guess you'll have to look real hard.
幸好我的视力特别棒
Good thing I have 20/20 vision, huh?
她现在在哪里  沃克
Where is she now, Walker?
-你知道吗  -我们不知道  巴基
- Do you know? - No, we don't know, Bucky.
但我们迟早会找到她的
It's only a matter of time before we find out.
你肯定很吃力吧  沃克
Things are really intense for you, aren't they, Walker?
冷静一点  沃克说得没错
Take it easy. Look, Walker's right.
我们必须找到他们  并阻止他们
It is imperative that we find them and stop them.
但是你们有干涉限制
But you guys have rules of engagement
还要申请各种授权
and all kind of authorizations you have to get.
我们都是自由人
We're free agents.
我们更灵活
We're more flexible.
所以我们也不该和你们一起行动
So it wouldn't make sense for us to work with you.
那就给你们一个建议
A word of advice, then.
少来碍我的事
Stay the hell out of my way.
斯洛伐克  布拉迪斯拉发
该死  我们得赶紧转移了
Damn it! We gotta move out now.
-他们找到我们了  -我们还有多少时间
- They found us. - How much time do we have?
没时间了  是权力掮客的人
None. It's The Power Broker's men.
所有人能拿多少拿多少
Everybody, grab what you can.
我能给你争取时间
I can give you time.
我拖住他们
I'll hold them off.
谢谢你
Thank you.
同一世界  同一类人
One world. One people.
快走
Let's go!
好了
All right,
站住  不许动
stop right there. Freeze!
开枪  打他
Hit him, open fire.
他们跑了
They got away.
你怎么想
So what are you thinking?
我知道我们要做什么
Well, I know what we have to do.
以赛亚说"我的同类"时
When Isaiah said "My people"...
别往心里去  他不是那个意思
Oh, don't take that to heart. That's not what he meant.
不  他说的是九头蛇
No, he meant HYDRA.
以前  九头蛇才是我的同类
HYDRA used to be my people.
不可能
Not a chance.
沃克毫无头绪
Walker doesn't have any leads.
我知道你想干什么  不行
I know where you're going with this, no.
他知道九头蛇所有秘密  你忘了西伯利亚的事了吗
He knows all of HYDRA's secrets. Don't you remember Siberia?
你就打算和那家伙坐下来好好聊聊吗
So you're just gonna go sit in a room with this guy?
是的
Yes.
那好吧
Okay, then.
我们去见泽莫
We're gonna go see Zemo.